# GOLLAPUDI VENKATA SAI REVATHI

revathigollapudi15@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/revathi-gollapudi-a60894187/ | +1-716-348-4485

### Summary

Graduate student in Computer Science at the University at Buffalo with 2.5 years of professional experience in software development and data management.

Proficient in Python, React, SQL, JavaScript, C#, Data Structures and Algorithms, with a track record of successful Sentiment Analysis, Quiz Play, and Hospital Management System projects.

Recognized for excellence, with accolades for outstanding contributions and holds certifications, including Azure Fundamentals.

### Work Experience

Sumitomo Buffalo, NY

Student Support Intern May 2024 - Present Developed and implemented over 10 dynamic forms using React for the frontend and Node.js for the backend, with

seamless data management in MSSQL Server using Sequelize and SQL. Designed and managed the complete form workflow, including creation, updation, closures, printing with required

format, tracking, emailing, and integration of a digital signature process.

• Developed and maintained RESTful APIs, ensuring smooth integration between front-end and back-end components.

Utilized Git for version control, ensuring code integrity and seamless collaboration across the development team.

• Transitioned the process from a manual, Excel-based system to a fully electronic and standardized platform which increased form workflow speed by 50% and data accuracy by 60%.

Hyderabad, India Deloitte Analyst - Full Time June 2021 - July 2023

• Reduced production issues by 10% through strategic bug resolution and optimized code enhancements using C#, significantly improving system stability.

Achieved complete automation of data processing workflows (100%) by implementing Azure Functions in C# within the Visual Studio IDE, streamlining operations and boosting efficiency.

Enhanced cross-platform data integration by seamlessly integrating SharePoint API with REST API and CSOM, leading to more efficient and reliable data exchanges.

• Optimized database performance by developing and deploying 20+ stored procedures and 50+ advanced SQL queries, resulting in faster and more efficient data retrieval and processing.

Resolved over 100 ServiceNow tickets, ensuring prompt and effective issue resolution, contributing to consistent project timelines and overall client satisfaction.

Deloitte Hyderabad, India InternJanuary 2021 - March 2021

• Received comprehensive training in C# and the .NET framework, enhancing proficiency in software development, and gained training in Agile methodologies and project management principles.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript.

Web Technologies: React, HTML, CSS.

Databases: SQL Server, PostgreSQL.
Others: Sequelize, NodeJS, .NET Framework, Bootstrap, SharePoint, Tableau, Version Control(Git), REST API, LINQ, Postman, Azure Fundamentals, SSRS, Visual Studios, Machine Learning, Data-Intensive Computing, Data Analysis, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Algorithms, Agile Methodologies, Artificial Intelligence, CSOM.

### Projects

Hospital Management System: Implemented a comprehensive hospital database system that organizes and manages data related to doctors, patients, diagnoses, and other critical details, significantly improving communication and operational efficiency within healthcare facilities. This initiative resulted in a 20% boost in operational efficiency.

Quiz Play: Engineered a user-centric quiz website with a responsive front-end interface and incorporated interactive features and real-time feedback mechanisms to enhance user engagement and satisfaction, promoting increased participation and enjoyment.

Sentiment Analysis Using Machine Learning: Developed a sentiment analysis model to classify emotions. Leveraged torchyision and OpenCV for data visualization. Utilized a VGG architecture with dropout, regularization, image augmentation, etc to prevent overfitting and manage gradient issues, achieving a 95% prediction accuracy.

# EDUCATION

### University at Buffalo, State University of New York

Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 3.8

Buffalo, NY

August 2023 - Present

GITAM Deemed to be University

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering; CGPA: 8.64

Visakhapatnam, India June 2017 - May 2021

# CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

Azure-900, Fundamentals of Azure Certification.

- Web Design for Everybody' by the University of Michigan: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript on Coursera.
- Machine Learning course by Internshala.
- Safe for team certification.

### Extracurricular Activities

- Part-time employee at the university's campus dining and shops, working 15–20 hours per week.
- Won second place in district-level long jump.
- Have organized the GUSAC Carnival as part of the Public Relations domain.

# Achievements and Awards

- Received the 'SPOT' and 'You are a GEM' awards from Deloitte.
- Received appreciation from leadership for closing 100+ ServiceNow tickets in just a few months.